The Sidney Rose Collection of Gilbert and Sullivan
Yale University Music Library
The Sidney Rose Collection of Gilbert and Sullivan
1880-1951
MSS 12
Yale University Music Library
12
(16 boxes)
Scores, libretti, and songs by Gilbert and Sullivan; articles, programs posters, parodies, satires, and cartoons relating to Gilbert and Sullivan; and a model theater of the original production of The Mikado
Rose, Sidney
Conditions Governing Access
The Collection is open to researchers by appointment. There are no restricted materials in the collection. Please contact the Special Collections staff to schedule an appointment.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
The Sidney Rose Collection of Gilbert and Sullivan was purchased by the Music Library of Yale University from Rose's sister in 1972.
Arrangement
In 13 series as follows: I. Piano-vocal scores. II. Libretti. III. Photographs and pictures. IV. Satire, parody, biography, critical commentary, letters, and miscellany. V. Periodicals and souvenir programs. VI. News clippings. VII. Programs. VIII. Piano-vocal arrangements of selections from the operettas. IX. Sheet music. X. Posters and graphics. XI. Bab ballads and orchestral parts. XII. Scrapbook. XIII. Miscellanea.
Scope and Contents
The Collection contains a wide range of materials which include: scores and libretti for the operettas; individual songs with words or music by Gilbert or Sullivan; programs and posters; parodies, satires, and cartoons directed at the operettas and their creators; a model theater of the original production of The Mikado; and a large number of newspaper and periodical articles pertaining to specific productions, revivals, and performers.
Biographical / Historical
The Sidney Rose Collection of Gilbert and Sullivan was collected by Rose for a history of Gilbert and Sullivan production in the United States. Rose never completed this work, though he did write an article entitled "Half a Century of Pinafore," (Musical Digest, June 1928).
Opera -- Production and direction -- United States; Operas -- Librettos; Operas -- Vocal scores with piano; Carte, Richard D'Oyly, 1844-1901; Gilbert, W. S. (William Schwenck), 1836-1911 -- Stage history -- 1800-1950; Sullivan, Arthur, 1842-1900
- Piano-vocal scores, Series I
  - Trial by jury, a novel and original dramatic cantata by Arthur Sullivan and W.S. Gilbert. Boston, O. Ditson & Co.; New York, C.H. Ditson & Co.; Chicago, Lyon & Healy, [no date] (Box 1)
    General
    (2 copies)
  - Selections from the Sorcerer, an original modern comic opera in two acts written by W.S. Gilbert and composed by Arthur Sullivan. Boston, [Oliver Ditson & Co.], [no date] (Box 1)
  - H.M.S. Pinafore, or the lass who loved a sailor, an entirely original nautical comic opera in two acts, written by W.S. Gilbert, composed by Arthur Sullivan. Boston, O. Ditson & Co. [no date] (Box 1)
    (1st. American edition?)
    (4 copies)
  - Selections from H.M.S. Pinafore, composed by Arthur Sullivan. Boston, O. Ditson & Co. (Box 1)
  - Selections from H. M. S. Pinafore and Trial by jury. Boston, Oliver Ditson & Co. [no date] (Box 1)
  - Iolanthe, or the peer and peri, written by W.S. Gilbert composed by Arthur Sullivan. Boston, O. Ditson [c.1882] (Box 1)
    "Authorized copyright edition, copyright 1882 by J. M. Stoddart.
    (first American edition?)
  - Ruddygore, or, the witch's curse! by W.S. Gilbert and Arthur Sullivan. Arrangement for pianoforte by George Lowell Tracy. New York, Wm A. Pond & Co.; Chicago, Chicago Music Co.; London, Chappell & Co. c1887. (Box 1)
  - Utopia, Limited, or the flowers of progress, an original comic opera in two acts, written by W.S. Gilbert, composed by Arthur Sullivan. Arranged from the full score by Ernest Ford. London, Chappell & Co. c1893. (Box 1)
  - Cox and Box, or the long lost brothers. New York, Norman L. Munro [no date] (Box 1)
  - Story and music arrangements adapted from Gilbert and Sullivan, by Opal Wheeler. Illustrated by Fritz Kredel. New York, E.P. Dutton and Co., 1946. (Box 1)
  - Patience, or Bunthorne's bride. (Comic aesthetic opera) written by W.S. Gilbert, composed by Arthur Sullivan. New York, Hitchcock Publishing House. c1881 by J.M. Stoddard & Co. (Box 2)
  - Patience, or Bunthorne's bride. (Comic aesthetic opera) written by W.S. Gilbert, composed by Arthur Sullivan. New York, Hitchcock Publishing House. To be had also at 25 Ann Street, Cor. Nassau Street. c1881 by J.M. Stoddard & Co. (Box 2)
  - Patience, or Bunthorne's bride. (Comic aesthetic opera) written by W.S. Gilbert, composed by Arthur Sullivan. Philadelphia, J.M. Stoddart & Co. c1881 (Box 2)
    ("Authorized copyright edition)
  - Patience, or Bunthorne's bride. (Comic aesthetic opera) written by W.S. Gilbert, composed by Arthur Sullivan. New York, Wm. A. Pond & Co. c1881 by J. M. Stoddart & Co. (Box 2)
  - Patience, or Bunthorne's bride. (Comic aesthetic opera) written by W.S. Gilbert, composed by Arthur Sullivan. Boston, Mass.: Oliver Ditson & Co. c1881 by J. M. Stoddard & Co. (Box 2)
  - Vocal gems from the new opera, Patience, or Bunthorne's bride. Written by W.S. Gilbert, composed by Arthur Sullivan. [Philadelphia] J. M. Stoddart & Co., c1881. (Box 2)
  - The pirates of Penzance, or the slave of duty. An entirely original comic opera in two acts, written by W.S. Gilbert, composed by Arthur Sullivan. London, Chappell & Co. [1880?] (Box 2)
    [1st ed.?]
  - The pirates of Penzance, or the slave of duty. An entirely original comic opera in two acts, written by W.S. Gilbert. Composed by Arthur Sullivan. [New York, Hitchcock Publishing Co.] c1880 by J. M. Stoddard & Co. [Owned by Hitchcock Publishing Co., New York (Box 2)
  - The pirates of Penzance, or the slave of duty. An entirely original comic opera in two acts, written by W.S. Gilbert, composed by Arthur Sullivan. [New York, Hitchcock Publishing Co.] c1880 by J. M. Stoddart & Co. To be had also at 7 Barclay Street, near Broadway. (Box 2)
    (3 copies)
  - The yeoman of the guard, or the merryman and his maid, by W.S. Gilbert and Arthur Sullivan. Arrangement for pianoforte by Joseph H. Wadsworth (of Boston, USA) New York, Wm. A. Pond & Co.; Chicago, Chicago Music Co.; London, Chappell & Co. c1888. (Box 3)
  - Vocal Gems. The yeoman of the guard, or the merryman and his maid. by W.S. Gilbert and Arthur Sullivan. Arrangement for pianoforte by Joseph H. Wadsworth (of Boston, USA) Oliver Ditson & Co., Boston, Mass.; New York, C.H. Ditson & Co.; Philadelphia, J.E. Ditson & Co. c1888. (Box 3)
  - The Mikado, or the town of Titi-Pu. Arrangement for pianoforte by George Lowell Tracy (of Boston, U.S.A.) of the above-named opera, by W.S. Gilbert and Arthur Sullivan. New York, Wm. A. Pond & Co.; London, Chappell & Co. [no date] (Box 3)
    (2 copies; copy 2 lacks last page)
  - The Mikado, or the town of Titi-Pu. Arrangement for pianoforte by George Lowell Tracy (of Boston, U.S.A.) of the above-named opera by W.W. Gilbert and Arthur Sullivan. London, Chappell & Co.; New York, William A. Pond & Co. [no date] (Box 3)
  - Der Mikado. Operette in 2 Akten von W.S. Gilbert. Musik von Arthur Sullivan. Clavierauszug mit deutschem Text. Leipzig, Rob. Forberg; London, Chappell & Co. [no date] (Box 3)
  - The national Mikado folio, containing all the choic vocal and instrumental selections of this famous opera. Compiled by Chas. Fremont, Esq. Published by National Music Company, Chicago, Ill. c1886, by the National Music Co. [c1885 by the Windsor Music Co.] (Box 3)
  - Pianoforte arrangement of Princess Ida, or Castle Adamant, by W.S. Gilbert and Arthur Sullivan. By George L. Tracy. New York, Philadelphia, Longon, J.M. Stoddart & Co. c1884. (Box 3)
  - Vocal Gems. Pianoforte arrangement of Princess Ida, or Castle Adamant, by W.S. Gilbert and Arthur Sullivan. By George L. Tracy. New York, Philadelphia, London, J.M. Stoddart & Co., c1884. (Box 3)
  - The grand duke, or the statutory duel. A comic opera in two acts, written by W.S. Gilbert, composed by Arthur Sullivan. Arranged from the full score by Wilfred Bendall. London, Chappell & Co. 1896. (Box 3)
    (1st. edition?)
  - Boguet [sic] of comic songs, and The great Mikado folio. New York, Published by Richard A. Saalfield [c1885] (Box 4)
  - A selection of the most popular vocal compositions of Arthur Sullivan. Boston, Oliver Ditson & Co. [no date] (Box 4)
  - The beauty stone. An original romantic musical opera in three acts, by Arthur W. Pinero, J. Comyns Carr and Arthur Sullivan. Arranged from the full score by Wilfred Bendall. London, Chappell & Co.; agents: New York, Boosey & Co., c1898. (Box 4)
  - The emerald isle; or, the caves of Carrig-Cleena. A new and original comic opera in two acts. Written by Basil Hood. Composed by Arthur Sullivan and, Edward German. Arranged from the full score by Wilfred Bendall. London, Chappell & Co.; agents: New York, Boosey & Co. c1901 (Box 4)
    [Produced posthumously; principally harmonized and orchestrated by German after Sullivan's death.]
  - An entirely original comic opera in two acts, entitled The Mountebanks, written by W.S. Gilbert. Composed by Alfred Cellier. London, Chappell & Co.; agents: New York, Novello, Ewer & Co. c1892. (Box 4)
    [1st edition]
  - An entirely original comic opera in two acts, entitled The Mountebanks, written by W.S. W.S. Gilbert. Composed by Alfred Cellier. Arranged from the full score by Alfred Plumpton. London, Chappell & Co.; agents: New York, Novello, Ewer & Co. c1892. (Box 4)
  - Gems, or The Brigands, comic opera in three acts. Libretto by W.S. Gilbert. Music by J. Offenbach. The only authorized edition as performed at the Casino, New York, New York, Wm. A. Pond, c1889. (Box 4)
  - His Excellency, a comic opera in two acts. Written by W.S. Gilbert. Composed by F. Osmond Carr. London, Joseph Williams; New York, Edward Schuberth & Co. (J.F.H. Meyer) [c1894] (Box 4)
  - The prodigal son, an oratorio. The word selected entirely from the Holy Scriptures. The music composed by Arthur S. Sullivan. Boston, Oliver Ditson & Co. [no date] (Box 4)
  - The Contrabandista, or, the law of the ladrones. Comic opera in two acts. The libretto written by F.C. Burnand, the music composed by Arthur S. Sullivan. Pianoforte arrangement by the composer. London, Boosey & Co. [no date] (Box 4)
    (Boosey & Co's comic operettas and musical farces)
  - The chieftan, an original comic opera in two acts. Written by F.C. Burnand, composed by Arthur Sullivan. New York, Boosey & Co., c1895. (Box 4)
    (1st. ed.?)
  - The rose of Persia, or the story-teller and the slave. New comic opera, by Basil Hood and Arthur Sullivan. London, Chappell & Co.; London, Ascherberg, Hopwood, & Crew; New York, Chappell-Harms, 1900. (Box 4)
- Libretti, Series II
  - Thespis, 1 copy (Box 5)
  - The Sorcerer, 2 copies (Box 5)
  - The Pirates of Penzance, 5 copies (Box 5)
  - H.M.S. Pinafore, 7 copies (Box 5)
  - Princess Ida, 3 copies (Box 5)
  - Iolanthe, 8 copies (Box 5)
  - The Grand Duke, 2 copies (Box 5)
  - The Gondoliers, 3 copies (Box 5)
  - Ruddigore, 5 copies (Box 5)
  - Utopia Limited, 2 copies (Box 5)
  - The Mikado, 19 copies (Box 6)
  - Yeoman of the Guard, 5 copies (Box 6)
  - The Mountebanks, 3 copies (Box 6)
  - The Chieftain, 1 copy (Box 6)
  - Ivanhoe, 1 copy (Box 6)
  - Happy Arcadia, 1 copy (Box 6)
  - The Emerald Isle, 1 copy (Box 6)
  - Broken Hearts, 1 copy (Box 6)
  - On Bail, 1 copy (Box 6)
  - Creatures of Impulse, 1 copy (Box 6)
  - Pygmalion and Galatea, 1 copy (Box 6)
  - Charity, 1 copy (Box 6)
  - Engaged, 3 copies (Box 6)
  - Palace of Truth, 1 copy (Box 6)
  - Tom Cobb, 1 copy (Box 6)
  - Randall's Thumb, 1 copy (Box 6)
- Photographs, Series III
  - Photographs of Savoyard singers, actors, and actresses both in and out of costume. (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - Production pictures. (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - Character sheets for individual operettas. (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - Negatives. (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - Tradesmen's picture cards (Box 7, Folder 3)
    (color sketches of characters and scenes from the operettas)
  - Pictures of Gilbert, Sullivan, and D'Oyly Carte. (Box 7, Folder 3)
- Satire, parody, biography, critical commentary, letters, and miscellany, Series IV
  - Satires, parodies, cartoons, humourous views, games, and quizzes based on or directed at the Gilbert and Sullivan operettas. (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - Biographical and other data on D'Oyly Carte. (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - Critical commentary on the plays. (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - Theatrical events unrelated to but contemporary with Gilbert and Sullivan. (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - Embroidery pattern using a scene from Patience. (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - Suggestions for amateur productions of Gilbert and Sullivan. (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - Sketches and other miscellaneous writing by Gilbert. (Box 8, Folder 7)
  - Literature referring to Gilbert and Sullivan -- both the collaborations and the men. (Box 8, Folder 8)
  - Miscellany (Box 8, Folder 9)
    - Announcemnt of "A Grand Gilbert and Sullivan costume ball," held at the Hotel Cecil [London?] on December 4, 1925., a (Box 8, Folder 9)
    - Publisher's flyer from J.M. Dent & Sons, London, for the book: Gilbert and Sullivan: a critical appreciation of the Savoy opera, by A.H. Goodwin., b (Box 8, Folder 9)
    - Envelope containing 6 personal visiting cards of various persons., c (Box 8, Folder 9)
    - Publisher's flyer from Bass Publishers, New York, for the book: The merry gentlemen of Japan: The Mikado for children, adapted by H.W. Reiter and Shephard Chartoc; and for the book: The Gilbert and Sullivan operas: a concordance, by Frederick J. Halton., d (Box 8, Folder 9)
    - Exhibition catalogue: "A source of innocent merriment: an exhibition of Gilbert & Sullivan," from the Pierpont Morgan Library, November 17, 1950-February 16, 1951., e (Box 8, Folder 9)
      2 copies
    - London County Council. Indication of houses of historical interes in London. Part LVIII (Sir W.S. Gilbert) [and] (Sir John Tenniel). P.S. King & Sons, agents, 1931., f (Box 8, Folder 9)
    - Program of events, the Gilbert and Sullivan Society, season 1934-1935., g (Box 8, Folder 9)
    - Standard Theatre: R. D'Oyly Carte's original company in Patience as seen by Mr. Cvrl Darling and Miss Mvrry Hill from ye orchestra stalls. Illustrated by Chas. Kendrick. [London?] J.M. Stoddard & Co., c1881., h (Box 8, Folder 9)
    - typed letter (form) from the Gilbert,& Sullivan Society, August, 1925., i (Box 8, Folder 9)
    - Goldberg, Isaac. Gilbert & Sullivan a handbook to the famous operettas. Girard, Kansas: Haldeman-Julius Co., [c1923] (Little blue book; no. 476), j (Box 8, Folder 9)
    - The Bab ballads: Much sound and little sense. New York: Little Leather Library Corp., [no date], k (Box 8, Folder 9)
  - Letters and manuscripts (Box 8, Folder 10)
    - autograph letter signed to Rudolph Aronson, from John Stetson, August 20, 1889, a (Box 8, Folder 10)
      (on the stationary of the Globe Theatre, Boston, where Stetson was proprietor and manager)
    - autograph letter signed to Rudolph Aronson, from Luby Nicholls, June 22, 1889., b (Box 8, Folder 10)
    - typed letter to Rudolph Aronson, from Alex P. Browne, May 18, 1889, c (Box 8, Folder 10)
    - Three pages, in hand of Mrs. Rose accounting for the collection at its sale, giving item prices and the total cost., d (Box 8, Folder 10)
- Periodicals and souvenir programs, Series V
  - Complete periodicals with articles relating to Gilbert and Sullivan. (Box 9)
    Including various copies of:
    The Sphere
    The Mentor
    The Book Buyer
    The Cornhill Magazine
    The London Mercury
    The Bookman
    Harpers
    The Gilbert and Sullivan Journal
    The Art Interchange
    American Gilbert and Sullivan Quarterly
  - Miscellaneous souvenir programs with many photographs. (Box 9)
- News clippings, Series VI
  - Reviews and production announcements (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - D'Oyly Carte in America. Advertisements, interviews, and reviews. (Box 10, Folder 2)
  - Information pertaining to amateur, American productions. News clippings of announcements, reviews, children's productions, and pictures. (Box 10, Folder 3)
  - Television and film versions of the operettas: Posters and publicity pictures. (Box 10, Folder 4)
  - Knights of Song: a musical play based upon the lives of Gilbert and Sullivan. (Box 10, Folder 4)
  - Biographical and other personal data about Sullivan. (Box 10, Folder 5)
  - Biographical and other personal data about Gilbert. (Box 10, Folder 6)
  - Articles pertaining to the collaboration and the partnership. (Box 10, Folder 7)
  - Interviews with, biographical data for, and pictures of original Savoyard performers. (Box 10, Folder 8)
    See also 7/1
  - Cartoons and caricatures based upon the operettas. (Box 10, Folder 9)
    See also 8/1
  - Production pictures from newspapers and magazines. (Box 10, Folder 10)
    See also 7/2
  - Book and record reviews. (Box 10, Folder 11)
  - Song of a Savoyard and further details concerning The Knights of Song. (Box 10, Folder 12)
  - Adaptations (Box 10, Folder 13)
    a) The hot Mikado
    b) The swing Mikado
    c) Memphis bound
    d) Pins and needles
  - Miscellaneous newspaper and periodical clippings concerning various productions, trivia, etc. (Box 10, Folder 14)
  - Mikado fan cover. (Box 10, Folder 15)
- Programs, Series VII
  - Programs from first American performances along with other miscellaneous programs for the operettas. (Box 11)
- Piano-vocal arrangements of selections from the operettas, Series VIII
  - Piano-vocal arrangements of selections from the operettas (number of items in brackets): (Box 12)
    The Gondoliers (6)
    H.M.S. Pinafore (16)
    Iolanthe (16)
    The Mikado (29)
    Patience (7)
    The Pirates of Penzance (4)
    Princess Ida (2)
    The Sorcerer (4)
    Trial by jury (1)
    The Yeoman of the Guard (8)
  - Piano-vocal arrangements of selections from operettas resulting from other collaborations entered into by Gilbert and Sullivan. (Box 12)
    Come, Maragarita, come from The Martyr of Antioch
    Drinking song from The Rose of Persia
    Melodies from The Contrabandistas
    Selections from Cox and Box
    The rival serenaders from Cox and Box
    Vocal gems from Ivanhoe
- Sheet music, Series IX
  - Songs by Arthur Sullivan published singly or in small collections and not from the operettas. (Box 13)
    - Eight songs by A. Sullivan. New York: W. A. Pond, [18--] (Box 13)
    - Twelve songs by J.L. Molloy and A.S. Sullivan [s.l., s.n., 18--] (Box 13)
    - The absent-minded beggar. Words by Rudyard Kipling. N.Y.: Boosey, cl899. (Box 13)
    - The Chorister. Words by F.E. Westherly. [sic] Boston: L.P. Goullaud 118--1 (Box 13)
    - The Chorister. Words by F.E. Weatherly. Chicago: National Music Co. [18--] (Box 13)
    - Come gentle sleep: from Ivanhoe. [s.l.: s.n., 19--?] (Box 13)
    - Coming home: duett [sic] Words by R. Reece. Philadelphia.: W.R. Smith, 18--? (Box 13)
    - The distant shore. Words by W.S. Gilbert. Cincinnati: J. Church, [18--] (Box 13)
    - The distant shore. Words by W.S. Gilbert. London: Chappell, [18--] (Box 13)
    - I would I were a king, fair maid! Words by Victor Hugo [s.l., s.n., 18--] (Box 13)
    - In Arcady: song adapted to music from The Sorcerer. Words by F.E. Weathersley [sic] Boston: O. Ditson, c1881. (Box 13)
    - It came upon the midnight clear. Words by E.H. Sears. New York: B.W. Hitchcock, [18--] (Box 13)
    - Lasst mich träumen = Let me dream again. Leipzig: Bosworth. (Box 13)
    - Let me dream again. New York: W.A. Pond. (Box 13)
    - Let me dream again = Is this a dream? New York: R.A. Saalfiedl. (Box 13)
    - Let others seek the peaceful plan (from The Contrabandista) Words by F.C. Burnand. Boston: O. Ditson, [18--] (Box 13)
    - Little darling, sleep again, Chicago: National Music Co. [19--?] (Box 13)
    - Little maid of Arcadee. Words by W.S. Gilbert. Boston P. Goullaud. (Box 13)
    - Little maid of Arcadee. Words by W.S. Gilbert. London E. Ashdown. (Box 13)
    - Little maid of Arcadee. Words by W.S. Gilbert. New York C.H. Ditson. (Box 13)
    - Little maid of Arcadee. Words by W.S. Gilbert. New York W.A. Pond. (Box 13)
    - Little maid of Arcadee. Words by W.S. Gilbert. [s.l.: s.n.] (Box 13)
    - Looking back. Words by Louisa Gary [sic] Boston: O. Ditson. (Box 13)
    - Looking back. Words by Louisa Gray. Chicago: National Music Co. (Box 13)
    - Looking back. Words by Louisa Gray. Portland, Oregon: W.B. Allen. (Box 13)
    - The lost chord. Words by A.A. Proctor. Portland, Oregon: White, Smith & Co. (Box 13)
    - The lost chord. Words by A.A. Proctor. [s.l.]: W.A. Pond. (Box 13)
    - The lost chord. Words by A.A. Proctor. London: Boosey. (Box 13)
    - The maiden's story. Words by Emma Embury. Philadelphia: Lee & Walker, [18--] (Box 13)
    - The mother's dream: song. Words by W. Barnes. London: Boosey, [18--] (Box 13)
    - My dearest heart. New York: G. Schirmer. (Box 13)
    - My dearest heart. New York: T.B. Harms. (Box 13)
    - My dearest heart. Boston: White, Smith & Co. (Box 13)
    - My love beyond the sea. Words by J.P. Douglas. New York: B.W. Hitchcock, [18--] (Box 13)
    - O fair dove! O fond dove. Words by Jean Ingelow. Boston: O. Ditson [18--] (Box 13)
    - O fair dove! O fond dove. Words by Jean Ingelow. New York: Hamilton S. Gordon. (Box 13)
    - O mistress mine. Words by Shakespere [s.l., s.n., 18--] (Box 13)
    - Once again. Words by L.H. Lewin. Chicago: White, Smith & Co. (Box 13)
    - Once again. Words by L.H. Lewin. J.F.P. & Co. (Box 13)
    - Once again. Words by L.H. Lewin. London: Boosey. (Box 13)
    - Once again. Words by L.W. Lewin. New York: B.W. Hitchcock, [18--] (Box 13)
    - Once again. Words by L.H. Lewin. New York: W.A. Pond. (Box 13)
    - Only the night wind sighs alone. Words by F.C. Burnand. New York: B.W. Hitchcock, [18--] (Box 13)
    - The sailor's grave. Words by H.G. Lyte. Boston: O. Ditson. (Box 13)
    - The sailor's grave. Words by H.G. Lyte. London: E. Ashdown. (Box 13)
    - St. Agnes' Eve. Words by Alfred Tennyson. Philadelphia: A.H. Rosewig, c1884. (Box 13)
    - A shadow. Words by A. Proctor. New York.: W.A. Pond, [18--] (Box 13)
    - Song of peace. Words by Tom Taylor. Boston: Silver, Burdett & Co., [18--] (Box 13)
    - Thou'rt passing hence: the highland message. Written by Mrs. Hemans. London: Chappell & Co., [18--] (Box 13)
    - A weary lot is thine fair maid. Written by Sir Walter Scott. Baltimore: G. Willig, [18--] (Box 13)
  - Works by other composers
    - A summer night in Munich. New York: T.B. Harms & Co., Cellier, Alfred (Box 13)
    - Lass that loved a sailor., Dibdin, Charles (Box 13)
      pp. 421-2 excerpted from an unspecified anthology.
    - Go on talking, don't mind me. London: J. Bath., Grossmith, George (Box 13)
    - Princess Ida grand match. New York: Wm. A. Pond & Co., 1884., Rice, Edward E. (Box 13)
- Posters and graphics, Series X
  - Rolled Posters and other graphic displays (Box 14)
    - Patience at the Haverly Theater on 14th St. (Box 14)
    - The Mikado at the Grand Opera House (Box 14)
    - Ruddygore at the Leland Opera House (Box 14)
    - Kiraley Bros. Great Mikado Ballet (Box 14)
    - The Pirates of Penzance (Box 14)
    - The Micky-Doo (Box 14)
    - Iolanthe (Box 14)
    - The Gondoliers (Box 14)
    - Yum-Yum at her toilet (Box 14)
    - Cast of characters from the Mikado (Box 14)
    - Reproduction of the front page of the Daily Graphic Saturday, March 1, 1879 (The Pinafore Crisis) (Box 14)
    - The Sorcerer at the Academy of Music, January 31st (Box 14)
    - Company list of the Savoy with date of first appearance in a Gilbert and Sullivan opera (Box 14)
    - Poster for the movie The Great Gilbert and Sullivan (Box 14)
- Bab ballads and orchestral parts, Series XI
  - Bab Ballads Orchestral parts to the Pirates of Penzance (Box 15)
- Scrapbook, Series XII
  - Large scrapbook containing diverse and various newspaper clippings (also to be had on microfilm) (Box 16)